

OBJECTIVE

Envision to make a difference in everyday life. As an enthusiast of Research, Engineering, and Information Technology, pursue to develop myself professionally in the field of Information Technology, Engineering and Research with any organization that will make use of my analytical, software development, research and communication skills.

STRENGTHS

My strengths are my professional attitude, accuracy, adaptability, and zeal to learn more, to develop the highest ideals possible with my "cando-it" attitude. Passionate about Frontend Development and Business & Data Analytics. Experienced in HRIS systems and processes.

VITALS

EMAIL

alshafaraz.gazi@gmail.com

MOBILE +642 2309 6609

WEBSITE

https://www.linkedin.com/in/gazi-ah

ADDRESS

76 Stewart Drive Newlands Wellington 6037

ALSHAFARAZ HUSSAIN GAZI

FREELANCER | ENTERPRENUER | MANAGER

WORK EXPERIENCE

DUKES

MANAGER

20 AUGUST 2021 TO CURRENT

- 1. Full ownership of Retail financial planning and analysis function.
- 2. Tracked and analyzed sales and customer trends in order to maximize sales and revenue while minimizing expenses.
- 3. Develop monthly forecasts and budgets.
- 4. P&L management (sales, margin, OPEX forecasting and management).
- 5. Inbound and outbound logistics of goods and products. Conducting bi-monthly stock take.
- 6. Ensure best customer services is rendered by employees. Introduced customer benefits (Freebies system).

KEY ACHEIVEMENTS

- 1. Exceeded sales targets by 100% in 2021 2022.
- 2. Introduced green retailing strategies which lead to no wastage of goods and products.

GAZMU TECH

FREELANCER

23 MAY 2021 TO CURRENT

Core responsibility required to manage and maintain the client's website.

- A core productivity role involving the design and building of customer websites. Assisting customers with web support requests as necessary, such as day to day content edits, and design alterations.
- 2. Discuss customer needs with clients and establish specific customer preferences via telephone, and face to face.
- 3. Creating a design concept for signoff template and content build and liaise with customer for signoff.
- 4. Final checks and launch preparation for client websites.
- 5. Knowledge and Tools experienced with Silverstripe CMS, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, MySQL.

WEBSITE PROJECTS

1. Zil Barbers – Converting static HTML site to Silverstripe CMS.

GUEST TRACTION

WEB DESIGNER AND DEVELOPER

15 FEBRUARY 2021 TO 23 MAY 2021

Core responsibility required to manage and maintain the organization's website.

PERSONAL AND PROFESSIONAL ATTRIBUTES

- Time management effectively managing workloads to achieve deadlines
- Ability to adapt to different working environments
- Good organizational and communication skills
- Responsible and Reliable
- Energetic and Ambitious
- Professional Attitude
- Knowledge of customer service
- Highly motivated and team player
- Ability to work as part of a flexible team
- Able to deal pleasantly and professionally with people
- Willingness to learn and undertake self-development

SKILLS & ABILITIES

- Project management
- Software development and documentation (SDLC)
- Data Analysis Report designing, generating data dumps and data representations
- Database Administration
- Web Development/ Front-end
- Programming Languages:
 - ASP.NET, C#, VB, C++
 - MS SQL, PLSQL, MySQL
 - JavaScript, HTML(5), CSS(3), PHP
- Software Experience:
 - MS Office Tools, MS Visual Studio, MS SQL Server, IIS, SharePoint, Windows Server, Report Builder
 - IBM COGNOS
 - Ellucian Banner
 - PeopleAdmin eRecruit
 - Typo3/ WordPress
 - Lime Survey (Open Source)

HOBBIES

- # Making friends and socializing
- # Traveling and exploring new places
- # Music and movies
- # Reading stories fictious and nonfictious
- # Playing soccer
- # Helping others and networking

- A core productivity role involving the design and building of customer websites. Assisting customers with web support requests as necessary, such as day to day content edits, and design alterations.
- Discuss customer needs with the sales team and establish specific customer preferences via telephone, and sometimes face to face.
- 3. Creating a design concept for signoff template and content build and liaise with customer for signoff.
- 4. Final checks and launch preparation for client websites.
- Action relevant tickets via the ticketing system Keeping a detailed record of all customer contact through CRM (Zendesk) and logging billable and unbillable time on the CRM.
- 6. Work on product development with the development team.
- 7. Creative contribution to user experience and other visual elements.
- 8. Collaboration on feature suggestions for improving Guest Traction products and services.
- 6. Identifying areas of improvement and suggest them to team members.
- 7. Knowledge and Tools experienced with Silverstripe CMS, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, Zendesk, Adobe Photoshop.

WEBSITE PROJECTS

- 1. Amalfi Motor Lodge
- 2. Montana Lodge Motel
- 3. Tui Oaks Motel
- 4. Ashbrook Motel Taupo
- 5. Jasmine Court Motel, Piction

PRIDE LANDS LTD AND PRIDE CLOTHING NZ

WEB DEVELOPER

19 DECEMBER 2019 TO 12 FEBRUARY 2021

Core responsibility required to manage and maintain the organization's website.

- 1. Provide technical expertise and set up infrastructure as needed in a variety of web-based systems.
- 2. Monitor and implement updates and upgrades for all web-based platforms.
- 3. Handle web-related purchasing and manage web domains.
- 4. Provide technical support as needed for database and accounting software.
- 5. Document code following best practices.
- 6. Adherence to branding standards and guidelines.
- 7. Maintain a polished and organized web archive.
- 8. Collaborate with a graphic designer at the creation of a cohesive Pride identity.
- Designing new front-end UI/UX and prototype for responsive website
- Based on UX/UI design to code front-end website using Materialize CSS framework.
- 11. Developing an enrolment app using PHPMailer and MySQL.
- 12. Managing FTP file uploads, domains, and Email servers.

THE UNIVERSITY OF THE SOUTH PACIFIC – HUMAN RESOURCES DEPARTMENT ASSISTANT ANALYST PROGRAMMER

20 AUGUST 2018 TO 08 JULY 2019

Responsible for applications and database systems development, mostly integrating and automating manual processes. Cleaning data, preparing reports and analyses. Process re-engineering and workflow development for HR processes including the full spectrum of Employee Life Cycle.

PROJECTS

REFEREES

MR. MIKE WELLS

J.T Director

C Guest Traction

E mike@guesttraction.com

T +64 27 338 4133

R Manager

MR. MOSES ARIAMA

J.T Director of Success

C Pride Lands Ltd & Pride Clothing NZ

E moses@pridelands.co.nz

T +64 22 028 8007

R Former Manager

MR. IRFAAN KHAN

J.T Manager HRMIS

C The University of the South Pacific

E Irfaan.Khan@usp.ac.fj

T +679 323 2323

R Former Supervisor

MR. ONISIMO PASIKALI

J.T Manager ICT

C Fiji Development Bank

E Onisimo.Pasikali@fdb.com.fj

T +679 331 4866 (1103)

R Former Manager

VISA PERMITS

NEW ZEALAND

Type: Residence Class Visa (under

Partnership)

Expiry Date: Indefinite

- 1. Leave Management System (.NET, MVC, Layered Architecture)
- 2. HR Website

FIJI DEVELOPMENT BANK - ICT DEPARTMENT

PROGRAMMER

22 JUNE 2018 TO 17 AUGUST 2018

Responsible for continuous upgrades and maintenance of the Banking Management System. As well as well maintain the company's corporate website and the intranet.

PROJECTS

Initiated development and production of the following projects/systems:

- 1. Insurance Payments System (ASP.NET Web Forms)
- Complaints, Incidents & Compliments System (using MVC architecture)
- Continuous upgrades to FDB Intranet System (FDB Insider using WordPress CMS)

ASSISTANT PROGRAMMER

03 February 2017 to 21 June 2018

Responsible for assisting Programmers in the continuous upgrades and maintenance of the Banking Management System. As well as well maintain the company's corporate website and the intranet.

PROJECTS

Have successfully implemented the following projects:

- 1. HR Survey System (EES-2017) (using ASP.NET MVC)
- 2. Helpdesk System (using MVC architecture)
- Revamped Insurance Module (Core Banking Software) (ASP.NET Web Forms)
- 4. FDB Intranet System (using WordPress CMS)
- Lime Survey (open-source survey software) Surveys @ FDB Systems

EDUCATION

THE UNIVERSITY OF THE SOUTH PACIFIC

FEBRUARY 2016 TO NOVEMBER 2017

Completed Postgraduate Diploma Unclassified Studies. Majoring in Computer Science.

FEBRUARY 2010 TO NOVEMBER 2015

Attained Bachelor of Science. Awarded on 23 March 2016. Majors in Computer Science and Electrical Electronics Engineering.

LEADERSHIP

I have been bestowed with leadership responsibilities in many capacities.

AIESEC FIJI

FEBRUARY 2019 TO JUNE 2019 Director

JULY 2018 TO FEBRUARY 2019

Director | Member Committee Vice President Information Management | Team Leader Marketing & Communications

AUGUST 2017 TO JUNE 2018

Founding Member – Youth Empowerment Advocate

FIJI DEVELOPMENT BANK
14 February 2017 to 17 August 2018
OHS Representative